<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2.71 astronomy</title>
    <link>https://2.71astro.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on 2.71 astronomy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 21:45:12 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://2.71astro.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>DIY motor focuser</title>
      <link>https://2.71astro.com/articles/ticfocuser/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 11:54:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://2.71astro.com/articles/ticfocuser/</guid>
      <description>Initial note: I&#39;m currently using the INDI platform on Linux. Without developing a driver, this project won&#39;t work on ASCOM.
This is a project I actually finished many months ago. I wanted to extend my astrophoto setup with motor focuser and I haven&#39;t found any DIY focuser project which fullfils my requirements. So for these reasons I decided to create something from scratch:
 DIY focuser is much cheaper than a manufactured one, DIY is more fun, I wanted something small and simple for astrophotography, without an external controller, I wanted a focuser which can be connected directly to a computer (PC, Laptop or RaspberryPi), so USB seemed to be the best choice, As always I wanted something aesthetic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIY flatfield panel</title>
      <link>https://2.71astro.com/articles/flatfield_panel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 11:32:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://2.71astro.com/articles/flatfield_panel/</guid>
      <description>Summer is almost over, so I found some time to write down the first article.
Some time ago I started thinking about making good quality, from both technical and aesthetic point of view, flatfield panel which can be used in the field powered by 12V battery. Two obvious possibilities are to either buy a cheap LED panel lamp in a home-improvement store or buy a dedicated flatfield panel (like Aurora which I heard is great).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glossary &amp; abbreviations</title>
      <link>https://2.71astro.com/articles/glossary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 22:42:32 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://2.71astro.com/articles/glossary/</guid>
      <description>This is work in progress
ADU TODO
AFOV Apparent field of view - TODO
Airy disk TODO
Aperture TODO
arcsec / arcmin Seconds of arc / minutes of arc - it is a unit of angle equal to:
\[ 1\:arcmin = \frac{1}{60}\:degree \]
\[ 1\:arcsec = \frac{1}{60}\:arcmin = \frac{1}{3600}\:degree \]
Back-focus TODO
Bias frame TODO
Bortle Scale Nine level scale that qualifies night sky&#39;s brightness. It is used to measure light pollution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why this page exists</title>
      <link>https://2.71astro.com/about/why/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 15:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://2.71astro.com/about/why/</guid>
      <description>For the last few years, my hobby is astronomy. During that time I had to figure out many details in the area of optics, photography, equipment and to some degree physics. What is a difference between MAK and SCT, what kind of eyepiece should I buy, what camera is the best for me and still in the budget and how to connect all these pieces, etc.
So far I haven&#39;t found a place where all this information is together in the form and detail I expect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why 2.71</title>
      <link>https://2.71astro.com/about/why271/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://2.71astro.com/about/why271/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s a tribute to one of the greatest mathematicians.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My equipment</title>
      <link>https://2.71astro.com/about/equipment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://2.71astro.com/about/equipment/</guid>
      <description>Here is my current equipment:
 Skywatcher Maksutov-Newtonian 190mm f/5.3, upgraded with Baader Diamond Steeltrack focuser EQ6-R Celestron Luminos 7mm, 15mm, 23mm Celestron Luminos 2.5x barlow lens Main camera: ZWO ASI1600mm Pro Guider/planetary camera: ZWO ASI290mc ZWO OAG, ZWO EFWmini filter wheel, ZWO LRGB 31mm filters DIY robofocuser (article to be written) DIY Li-ion 320Wh battery pack (article to be written) DIY flatfield panel Intel NUC with Archlinux/Indi/KStars/Ekos software to control the equipment  What I used in the past:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>